<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<wiki>
  <title>Windsor, Ontario</title>
  <Summary>
Windsor, the southern-most city in Ontario, is known as one of the  busiest border cities in Canada. Although Windsor is not as large a city as Toronto and does not provide such a large surge of tourism, Windsor provides cross-border attraction with a beautiful riverside view.
  </Summary>
  <History>
Prior to European exploration and settlement, the Windsor area was inhabited by the First Nations and Native American people. Windsor was first settled in 1749 as a French agricultural settlement, making it the oldest continually inhabited settlement in Canada west of Montreal. The area was first named Petite Côte ("Little Coast" - as opposed to the longer coastline on the Detroit side of the river), and later became known as La Côte de Misère ("Poverty Coast") because of the sandy soils near LaSalle. Windsor's French heritage is reflected in many French street names such as Ouellette, Pelissier, François, Pierre, Langlois, Marentette, and Lauzon. There is a significant French-speaking minority in Windsor and the surrounding area, particularly in the Lakeshore, Tecumseh and LaSalle areas. The current street system of Windsor (a grid with elongated blocks) reflects the French method of agricultural land division where the farms were long and narrow, fronting along the river. Today, the north-south street name often indicates the name of the family that at one time farmed the land. The street system of outlying areas is consistent with the British system for granting land concessions.
  </History>
  <Geography>
Windsor is the southernmost city in Ontario
  </Geography>
  <Government>
Windsor's history as an industrial centre has given the New Democrats (a party partially founded, governed and supported by labour unions), a dedicated voting base. During federal and provincial elections, Windsorites have maintained its local representation in the respective legislatures. The Liberal Party of Canada also has a strong electoral history in the city. Canada's 21st Prime Minister Paul Martin was born in Windsor. His father Paul Martin (Sr.), a federal cabinet minister in several portfolios through the Liberal governments of the 1940s, 1950s and 1960s, was first elected to the House of Commons from a Windsor riding in the 1930s. Martin (Sr.) practiced law in the city and the federal building on Ouellette Avenue is named after him. Eugene Whelan was a Liberal cabinet minister and one-time Liberal party leadership candidate elected from Essex County from the 1960s to the early 1980s, as well as Mark MacGuigan of Windsor-Walkerville riding, who also served as External Affairs, and later Justice minister in the early 1980s. Herb Gray represented Windsor as an MP from 1962 through 2003, winning thirteen consecutive elections making him the longest serving MP in Canadian history. A bust of Herb Gray is located at the foot of Ouellette Avenue near Dieppe Park in downtown Windsor.

  </Government>
  <Attractions></Attractions>
  <Events></Events>
  <References>Sample text (Government, History) from Windsor, Ontario Wikipedia entry</References>
  <Links></Links>
</wiki>
